Guide to the Abe Fortas Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Board and Committee Memberships, 1947-1982; Series VI
  As a leading legal advocate and as a friend and advisor to President Johnson, Fortas found himself serving on many committees charged with the task of developing and amending laws and procedures through a wide array of judicial, administrative, governmental, and private boards and committees. Fortas's abiding interest in civil liberties, equal treatment and opportunity under the law, the legal treatment of the indigent and the insane, and the use and abuse of narcotic drugs in society, are all well documented in this series. Fortas's leading role on two presidential committees on equal employment opportunity, and his long involvement with the Washington School of Psychiatry (an affiliate of the William Alanson White Psychiatric Foundation and the A. K. Rice Institute) are also well documented.
  - Administrative Conference of the United States
    - Committee on Personnel
      - Agendas and minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 164, Folder 1 - 2)
      - Bulletins, 1961-1962 (Box 164, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence and memoranda
        - May 1961 - November 1962 (Box 164, Folder 4 - 8)
        - December 1962 - September 1964 (Box 165, Folder 9)
      - Recommendation of the committee, 1961-1962 (Box 165, Folder 10 - 13)
      - Reports
        - November 1961 - June 1962 (Box 165, Folder 14)
        - July 1962 - August 1963 (Box 166, Folder 15 - 16)
      - Supporting documentation, 1947-1962 (Box 166, Folder 17 - 18)
      - Working drafts, 1962 (Box 166, Folder 19)
  - Advisory Committee on Legal Services, 1981 (Box 166, Folder 20)
  - American Bar Association
    - Advisory Committee on Fair Trial and Free Press
      - January 1965 - July 1965 (Box 166, Folder 21)
      - August 1965 - November 1966 (Box 167, Folder 22)
    - Special Committee on Youth Education for Citizenship, 1979-1981 (Box 167, Folder 23 - 24)
  - American Bar Association and American Medical Association Joint Committee on Narcotic Drugs
    - General, 1955-1960 (Box 167, Folder 25 - 31)
    - Reports, 1958 (Box 168, Folder 32 - 34)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, National Capital Area, Board of Directors, 1961-1981 (Box 168, Folder 35)
  - American Economic Association, 1962-1963 (Box 168, Folder 36)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 168, Folder 37)
  - American Judicature Society, 1964-1966 (Box 168, Folder 38)
  - American Red Magen David for Israel
    - Correspondence and related material
      - 1976-1978 (Box 168, Folder 39 - 41)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 169, Folder 42 - 43)
    - Tribute to Emanuel Celler [includes photograph], 1977-1978 (Box 169, Folder 44)
  - Carnegie Hall Corporation and Society
    See also: Kennedy Center, Stevens, Roger L.
    - Certificates of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1979 (Box 169, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence
      - 1962-1980 (Box 169, Folder 46 - 51)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 170, Folder 52)
    - Board of Trustees
      - Minutes and reports
        - 1965-1975 (Box 170, Folder 53 - 59)
        - 1976-1982 (Box 171, Folder 60 - 65)
      - Notices and agendas, 1978-1982 (Box 171, Folder 66)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce, Economic Development Agency, 1980-1981 (Box 171, Folder 67)
  - College of the Virgin Islands, 1963-1981 (Box 172, Folder 68 - 69)
  - Federated Department Stores, 1960-1970 (Box 172, Folder 70)
  - Fund for Higher Education (in Israel) [includes photographs], 1971-1980 (Box 172, Folder 71 - 74)
  - Institute of Judicial Administration, Project on Anglo-American Administrative Law, 1968-1969 (Box 172, Folder 75 - 76)
  - Johns Hopkins University, School of Advanced International Studies, 1965-1971 (Box 172, Folder 77)
    See also: Series III. Speeches, Introduction of Senator J. William Fulbright, Johns Hopkins University, School of Advanced International Studies
  - Judicial Conference of the United States
    - Advisory Committee on Appellate Rules
      - Correspondence, 1974-1982 (Box 173, Folder 78 - 83)
      - Draft rules and related materials
        - 1974-January 1977 (Box 173, Folder 84 - 86)
        - February 1977-1980 (Box 174, Folder 87 - 89)
    - Advisory Committee on Criminal Rules
      - Agendas and minutes, 1960-1965 (Box 174, Folder 90 - 91)
      - Background materials, 1956-1964 (Box 174, Folder 92 - 93)
      - Comments on rules
        - 1961-April 1963 (Box 174, Folder 94)
        - May 1963-1965 (Box 175, Folder 95)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 175, Folder 96 - 98)
      - Department of Justice comments on Rule 16, 1963 (Box 175, Folder 99 - 100)
      - Drafts of rules
        - 1961-August 1962 (Box 175, Folder 101 - 102)
        - October 1962-1965 (Box 176, Folder 103 - 105)
      - Survey of circuit judges on Rule 32(c)(2), 1964 (Box 176, Folder 106)
      - Survey of district judges on Rule 32(c)(2), 1964 (Box 176, Folder 107 - 110)
  - Judicial Conference of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit
    - Committee on Abolishment of Mandatory Capital punishment, 1959-1961 (Box 177, Folder 111)
    - Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, Rule 5(a), 1958 (Box 177, Folder 112)
    - Indigency and appointment of counsel, 1962 (Box 177, Folder 113)
    - Juvenile courts, 1958-1962 (Box 177, Folder 114 - 117)
    - Mental disorders, 1962-1965 (Box 177, Folder 118)
  - John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts
    - Alliance for Arts Education, 1970-1977 (Box 177, Folder 119 - 120)
    - American Film Institute, Inc.
      - 1972-1973 (Box 177, Folder 121)
      - 1974-1978 (Box 178, Folder 122 - 124)
    - American National Theater & Academy, 1981-1982 (Box 178, Folder 125)
    - Becker, Ralph E., 1967-1976 (Box 178, Folder 126)
    - Becker, William W., 1974-1977 (Box 178, Folder 127)
    - Bicentennial Theater Festival [includes photograph], 1972-1975 (Box 178, Folder 128)
    - Board of Trustees
      - Correspondence, 1964-1981 (Box 178, Folder 129 - 131)
      - Minutes, 1970-1981 (Box 179, Folder 132 - 135)
      - Notices and agendas, 1971-1982 (Box 179, Folder 136)
    - Bonds, 1977-1980 (Box 179, Folder 137)
    - Budgets
      - 1965-April 1975 (Box 179, Folder 138 - 139)
      - May 1975-1982 (Box 180, Folder 140 - 143)
    - Casals Istomin, Marta, 1979-1981 (Box 180, Folder 144)
    - Construction claims
      - May 1966-October 1973 (Box 180, Folder 145 - 147)
      - August 1966-November 1976 (Box 181, Folder 148 - 149)
    - Corporate Fund for the Performing Arts, 1974-1979 (Box 181, Folder 150)
    - Deferred giving program, 1976 (Box 181, Folder 151)
    - Executive Committee
      - Correspondence, 1966-1981 (Box 181, Folder 152)
      - Minutes, 1965-1982 (Box 181, Folder 153 - 156)
      - Notices and agendas, 1966-1982 (Box 181, Folder 157)
    - Feinstein, Martin, 1972-1979 (Box 182, Folder 158)
    - Founding materials and publications, 1958-1972 (Box 182, Folder 159)
    - Friends of the Kennedy Center, 1965-1982 (Box 182, Folder 160 - 164)
    - General correspondence, 1966-1982 (Box 182, Folder 165)
    - Golden Circle Club, 1973-1981 (Box 182, Folder 166)
    - Honors Gala, 1978-1981 (Box 182, Folder 167)
    - Institute/conservatory for the performing arts, 1981-1982 (Box 182, Folder 168)
    - Kendrick, Thomas R., 1977-1981 (Box 183, Folder 169)
    - Kennedy family, 1966-1979 (Box 183, Folder 170)
      See also: Kennedy Center Productions, Inc.
    - Labor, 1970-1981 (Box 183, Folder 171 - 173)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities/National Endowment for the Arts, 1966-1977 (Box 183, Folder 174)
    - National Park Service, 1972-1976 (Box 183, Folder 175)
    - National Symphony Orchestra, 1970-1976 (Box 183, Folder 176)
    - New National Theatre, Inc., 1974-1981 (Box 183, Folder 177 - 178)
    - Performance of the Month Club, 1981 (Box 183, Folder 179)
    - Performing Arts Library, 1979 (Box 184, Folder 180)
    - Poole, Jillian, 1975-1976 (Box 184, Folder 181)
    - President's Advisory Committee on the Arts, 1970-1980 (Box 184, Folder 182)
    - Program Committee, 1966-1972 (Box 184, Folder 183)
    - Stevens, Roger L., 1965-1981 (Box 184, Folder 184 - 186)
    - Studio/Terrace Theater
      - Correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box 184, Folder 187 - 190)
      - Deed of Trust, 1975-1977 (Box 185, Folder 191)
      - Financial materials, 1976-1979 (Box 185, Folder 192 - 195)
      - Friday Morning Music Club, 1977 (Box 185, Folder 196)
      - Theater Chamber Players, 1976-1981 (Box 185, Folder 197 - 198)
    - Tickets/sales, 1975-1981 (Box 185, Folder 199)
    - Washington Opera, 1979-1980 (Box 185, Folder 200)
    - Westport Country Playhouse/Connecticut Theater Foundation, 1977 (Box 185, Folder 201)
  - Kennedy Center Productions, Inc.
    - American Music Theater Group, 1980 (Box 185, Folder 202)
    - Audits
      - 1972 (Box 185, Folder 203)
      - 1973-1981 (Box 186, Folder 204 - 205)
    - Contract and cooperation agreements, 1971-1974 (Box 186, Folder 206)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 186, Folder 207 - 213)
    - Financial materials, 1971-1982 (Box 187, Folder 214 - 221)
    - Minutes
      - 1972-January 1973 (Box 187, Folder 222)
      - February 1973-1982 (Box 188, Folder 223 - 227)
    - Productions
      - Annie, 1977-1981 (Box 188, Folder 228 - 229)
      - Caesar and Cleopatra, 1976-1977 (Box 188, Folder 230)
      - Fiddler on the Roof, 1976-1977 (Box 188, Folder 231 - 232)
      - First Monday in October, 1977-1980 (Box 188, Folder 233)
      - Mass, 1971-1975 (Box 189, Folder 234)
      - The Merchant, 1976-1977 (Box 189, Folder 235)
      - Montparnasse, 1975 (Box 189, Folder 236)
      - Odyssey/Home Sweet Homer, 1974-1976 (Box 189, Folder 237 - 240)
      - The Texas Trilogy, 1976-1977 (Box 189, Folder 241)
      - Timbuktu, 1977 (Box 189, Folder 242)
  - Marlboro School of Music
    - Correspondence
      - 1970-May 1978 (Box 189, Folder 243 - 244)
      - June 1978-1982 (Box 190, Folder 245 - 246)
    - Financial materials, 1974-1982 (Box 190, Folder 247)
    - Meeting agendas and notices, 1974-1982 (Box 190, Folder 248)
    - Meeting minutes, 1974-1981 (Box 190, Folder 249 - 250)
  - National Citizens Committee for Community Relations, 1964 (Box 190, Folder 251)
  - National Guild of Community Music Schools, 1970-1973 (Box 190, Folder 252 - 253)
  - National Symphony Orchestra
    - Board of Directors
      - Correspondence
        - 1966-October 1977 (Box 190, Folder 254 - 255)
        - November 1977-1981 (Box 191, Folder 256)
      - Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 191, Folder 257)
    - Executive Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 191, Folder 258)
    - Financial materials, 1972-1977 (Box 191, Folder 259)
  - President's Advisory Commission on Narcotic and Drug Abuse, 1963-1964 (Box 191, Folder 260)
  - President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity
    - Community Leaders' Conference Report, 1962 (Box 191, Folder 261)
    - Correspondence
      - 1960-April 1963 (Box 191, Folder 262 - 265)
      - May 1963-1965 (Box 192, Folder 266 - 267)
    - Drafts of executive orders, 1960-1963 (Box 192, Folder 268 - 271)
    - Hanford Nuclear Reservation, 1962-1963 (Box 192, Folder 272)
    - Kheel Report, 1962 (Box 192, Folder 273)
    - Memoranda, 1962-1963 (Box 192, Folder 274)
    - National Labor Relations Board, 1961 (Box 192, Folder 275)
    - Nixon Committee Report, 1960-1961 (Box 192, Folder 276)
    - Report to the President, 1963 (Box 193, Folder 277)
    - Rules and regulations, 1961-1963 (Box 193, Folder 278 - 280)
    - Subcommittee on Review and Enforcement, 1960 (Box 193, Folder 281)
  - President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity in the Armed Forces
    - Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 193, Folder 282 - 284)
    - Reports, 1962-1965 (Box 194, Folder 285 - 288)
    - Air Force questionnaire, 1963 (Box 194, Folder 289)
    - Air Force Reserve materials, 1962 (Box 194, Folder 290)
    - Air Force Reserve questionnaire, 1962-1963 (Box 194, Folder 291)
    - Army materials, 1962 (Box 194, Folder 292)
    - Army materials, 1962 (Box 195, Folder 293)
    - Army questionnaire, 1962-1963 (Box 195, Folder 294)
    - Army Reserve materials, 1962 (Box 195, Folder 295)
    - Army Reserve questionnaire, 1963 (Box 195, Folder 296)
    - Marine Corps materials, 1962 (Box 195, Folder 297)
    - Marine Corps questionnaire, 1963 (Box 195, Folder 298)
    - National Guard materials, 1962 (Box 195, Folder 299 - 300)
    - National Guard questionnaire
      - 1962-May 1963 (Box 195, Folder 301)
      - June 1963 (Box 196, Folder 302)
    - Navy materials, 1962 (Box 196, Folder 303)
    - Navy questionnaire, 1962-1963 (Box 196, Folder 304)
    - Navy and Marine Corps Reserves materials, 1962 (Box 196, Folder 305)
    - Navy and Marine Corps Reserves questionnaire, 1963 (Box 196, Folder 306)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial Foundation, 1963-1965 (Box 196, Folder 307)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Centennial, 1981-1982 (Box 196, Folder 308)
  - Russell Sage Foundation, 1966-1969 (Box 196, Folder 309 - 312)
  - Synagogue Council of America, Bicentennial Committee, 1975 (Box 197, Folder 313)
  - University of California, Berkeley, Welfare Law Project, 1965 (Box 197, Folder 314)
  - University of Chicago Law School
    - Arbitration project, 1957-1958 (Box 197, Folder 315)
    - Law and Behavioral Science Advisory Committee, 1954-1958 (Box 197, Folder 316 - 317)
    - Visiting Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 197, Folder 318)
  - Washington School of Psychiatry
    - Correspondence
      - 1950-March 1958 (Box 197, Folder 319 - 322)
      - April 1958-1981 (Box 198, Folder 323 - 330)
    - Publications, 1969-1974 (Box 198, Folder 331 - 332)
  - White House Conference on Narcotic and Drug Abuse, 1962 (Box 198, Folder 333)
- Personal Papers, 1939-1982; Series VII
  The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material. The most useful materials in the series are the extensive autobiographical files that Fortas compiled for inclusion in various publications and for other publicity purposes.
  - Biographical sketches [includes photographs], 1939-1982 (Box 199, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Condolences on Fortas's death, 1982 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings about Fortas, 1966-1973 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Obituaries, 1982 (Box 199, Folder 6)
  - Passports [includes photographs], 1943-1968 (Box 199, Folder 7)
  - Supreme Court Memorial Resolutions, 1982 (Box 199, Folder 8)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1973, undated; Series VIII
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiotapes, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters, may not be played. Consult the finding aid and/or a reference archivist to determine availability of a use copy or the process required to generate a use copy.
  - "Katherine Graham/LBJ/ Abe Fortas, NBC TV" [reel-to-reel original tape; restricted], 1973 July 30 (Box 200)
  - "'LBJ' for Abe Fortas (2 sides)" [reel-to-reel original tape; restricted], undated (Box 201)
  - "Lyndon B. Johnson: A Week in the Life of the President" [reel-to-reel original tape; restricted], undated (Box 202)
- Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor Porter Financial Material, 1975-1979; Series IX
  Materials box 203 are restricted until January 1, 2020 due to attorney-client privelige.
  - Porter, Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor financial materials, 1975-1979 (Box 203, Folder 1)
    The materials in this Series are protected by attorney-client confidentiality and are restricted until January 2020.
- Additional Material, Circa 1974; Accession 2012-M-059
  - Unpublished typescript, "The Constitution and the Presidency," by former Supreme Court Justice Abe Fortas., Circa 1974 (Box 1)